# Luis López Díaz

Parranquilla, Atlántico(+57) 320 7757394□ llopeza@uninorte.edu.co

## MSc. Student in Electrical Engineering

#### **About**

MSc student in Electrical Engineering from Universidad del Norte. Electronic Engineer and Electrical Engineer graduated from Universidad del Norte. Luis is from Barranquilla. Luis is particularly interested in power systems, renewable energy and microgrids.

"I had a dream the other day that my research made the world a better placer" Jorge Cham

Education	
2443411011	
MSc. in Electrical Engineering	2018
Universidad del Norte	
Student	
Electrical Engineer	2013 - 2016
Universidad del Norte	
Electronics Engineer	2011 - 2015
Universidad del Norte	
Diplomado en Pedagogía Universitaria	2018
CEDU-Universidad del Norte	
Currently studying	
HP Accredited Technical Associate	2014
HP ExpertOne	
Electronics and measurements	2014
Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje (SENA)	
Short course	
Electromagnetic Spectrum - Introduction	2013
Agencia Nacional del Espectro (ANE)	
Short course	

## Experience

External consultant 2017 - 2018

Unión Temporal Iluminaciones Zona Bananera Technical advice on public lighting infrastructure

Profesor Catedrático Universidad del Norte - Dpto Ingeniería Eléctrica y Electrónica Circuitos II, Máquinas Eléctricas.	2016 - 2019
Electrical engineer  Unión Temporal Iluminaciones Zona Bananera  Technical and operational coordination of public lighting	2016 - 2018
Speaker  VIII International Bioengineering Seminar  Three-dimensional Heart Reconstruction using Computerized Axial Tomography Images	2016 - 2016
<b>Tutor</b> CREE Universidad del Norte Integral Calculus, Mechanical Physics, Signals and Systems, Elements of Power Systems.	2013 - 2015
Chair IEEE Uninorte Student Branch	2013 - 2014
Languages	
Spanish: Mother tongue English: B2	
Awards	
Silver Medal Universidad del Norte Electrical engineering	2016
Cum laude thesis Universidad del Norte System of Rendering and Visualization of Medical Images of the Heart	2016
Graduate of Excellence Universidad del Norte Electronics engieneering	2016
<b>Dean's List</b> Universidad del Norte	2014
Roble Amarillo Scholarship Universidad del Norte	2011

Andres Bello Adward 2010

Ministerio de Educación

Resolución 987 de 2011

Language and Philosophy territorial entity category

### Software skills

- MS Office
- AutoCad
- MATLAB
- PowerWorld
- Neplan
- DIgSILENT
- HTML

## **Hobbies**

Photgraphy, cycling, Rubiks Cubes, series (TV), coding.